export const GOVERNMENTA2019 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The constitutional power given to the judiciary to interpret legislative acts, executive and administrative actions and to declare its constitutionality or otherwise is _____",
A: "judicial power",
B: "separation of power",
C: "judicial review",
D: "administrative processes",
answer: "C. judicial review",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. The ultimate duty of a citizen is to demonstrate his/her __________",
A: "allegiance to the sovereign",
B: "loyalty to the state",
C: "respect for the national flag",
D: "contribution to government expenditure",
answer: "B. loyalty to the state",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Conventions and usages are rules based on ________",
A: "traditions and customs",
B: "previous constitutions",
C: "legal documents",
D: "decisions of commoners",
answer: "A. traditions and customs",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. The body responsible for the execution of the policies of government is the ______",
A: "Pressure group",
B: "Civil service",
C: "Constitutional Conference",
D: "Electoral Commission",
answer: "B. Civil Service",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The Electorate is defined as ________",
A: "intended candidates for voting",
B: "elected party members",
C: "elected civil society group",
D: "citizens that are qualified to vote",
answer: "D. citizens that are qualified to vote",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. The right to govern and administer the affairs of the people of a country is ________",
A: "power",
B: "diplomacy",
C: "authority",
D: "influence",
answer: "C. authority",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. One of the following is a characteristic of a unitary system",
A: "Heterogeneous society",
B: "Homogeneous society",
C: "Communal society",
D: "Feudal society",
answer: "B. Homogeneous society",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. The mass type of party is ________",
A: "broad-based",
B: "capitalist",
C: "feudalist",
D: "conservative",
answer: "A. broad-based",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Who among the following provided the detailed work on sovereignty?",
A: "Jean Bodin",
B: "Fredrick Englels",
C: "Bolaji Akinyemi",
D: "Thomas Hobbes",
answer: "A. Jean Bodin",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. The family and peer groups are important agents of _________",
A: "political culture",
B: "political socialization",
C: "charismatic authority",
D: "traditional authority",
answer: "B. political socialization",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. The confederal system of government is unpopular because ___________",
A: "the government operates oligarchy system",
B: "it does not follow due process",
C: "it discourages rapid development",
D: "all the component units are sovereign",
answer: "D. all the component units are sovereign",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Local government is relevant because it provides political ______",
A: "discussion among electorate",
B: "discipline among party members",
C: "representation in the judiciary",
D: "participation at the grassroots",
answer: "D. participation at the grassroots",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Provide group provide _______",
A: "manifestoes for political parties",
B: "sponsorship of candidates",
C: "aims and objectives for a wider to the electorate",
D: "means by which government ascertain public reactions to their policies",
answer: "D. means by which government ascertain public reactions to their policies",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. The authority of the state is collectively exercised by the _______",
A: "executive, legislative, judiciary",
B: "president, governor and chairman",
C: "police, army and navy",
D: "government, people and civil servants",
answer: "A. executive, legislature, and judiciary",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. In a presidential system of government, legislative approval is not necessary for the ________",
A: "appointment of supreme court judges",
B: "rectification of treaties",
C: "granting of pardons",
D: "appointments of civil servants",
answer: "D. appointment of civil servants",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. The following are the reasons widely espoused for military intervention and rules in West Africa except ______",
A: "Tribalism and Nepotism",
B: "inordinate ambition of soldiers",
C: "maladministration",
D: "religion",
answer: "D. religion",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Which of the following electoral systems is ideal for a heterogeneous society?",
A: "simple majority",
B: "preferential ballot",
C: "non-transferable vote",
D: "proportional representation",
answer: "D. Proportional representation",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. A constitution performs the role of ________",
A: "law making",
B: "law enforcement",
C: "communicating the ideals of leaders",
D: "stating the functions and limitations of leaders",
answer: "D. stating the functions and limitations of leaders",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Impeachment process is a unique feature of the ______",
A: "parliamentary system",
B: "presidential system",
C: "federal system",
D: "unitary system",
answer: "B. presidential system",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Which of the following is a function of the party whip?",
A: "flogging erring party members",
B: "ensuring that the members tow the party position",
C: "ensuring the safety of the speaker",
D: "assessing the performance of the law makers",
answer: "B. Ensuring that the members tow the party position",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Labour groups mostly come under the umbrella of the ________",
A: "industrial workers' union",
B: "trades union congress",
C: "anomic group",
D: "civil defence",
answer: "B. trade union congress",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. The major problem facing electoral management bodies in West Africa is _______",
A: "Lack of qualified personnel",
B: "poor communication network",
C: "foreign interference",
D: "electoral malpractice",
answer: "D. electoral malpractices",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. The features of a state include all the following except _______",
A: "government",
B: "territory",
C: "society",
D: "population",
answer: "C. society",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. To facilitate movement of people from one member to another the Economic Community of West  African States (ECOWAS) has _________",
A: "created several border posts within member states",
B: "waived visa requirements for citizens of member countries",
C: "created one currency for all member countries",
D: "maintained regional peace and security through deployment of forces",
answer: "B. waived visa requirements for citizens of member countries",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Public Corporations are referred to as statutory bodies because they are established by _________",
A: "a legislative instrument",
B: "Acts of parliament",
C: "an executive instrument",
D: "Bye-laws",
answer: "B. Acts of parliament",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Which state institution serves as a link between the government and the people ?",
A: "Office of the president",
B: "The civil service",
C: "the judiciary",
D: "the church",
answer: "B. The Civil Service",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. The media play a vital role in the political environment in that, it ________",
A: "articulates the views of individuals",
B: "incites people to be lawless",
C: "projects individuals above the state",
D: "articulates the views of the ruling party",
answer: "A. articulates the views of individuals",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Military might is a major determinant of a country's _______",
A: "independence",
B: "democracy",
C: "foreign policy",
D: "wealth",
answer: "C. foreign policy",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. The major role of minority parties in parliament is to _______",
A: "criticize every government policy",
B: "ensure democratic governance",
C: "monitor the activities of the president",
D: "supervise the passage of bills",
answer: "B. ensure Democratic governance",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. The political parties established in West Africa in the 1950's were aimed at ________",
A: "securing independence for their people",
B: "Participating in the colonial administration",
C: "introducing guerilla warfare against Europeans",
D: "representing their people in the British parliament",
answer: "A. securing independence for their people",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. The Commonwealth Secretariat is located in _________",
A: "Los Angeles",
B: "Kuala-Lumpur",
C: "London",
D: "Glasgow",
answer: "C. London",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Which colonial administration in West Africa sought to integrate her colonies with their home country?",
A: "British",
B: "Dutch",
C: "French",
D: "Danes",
answer: "C. French",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. The following are benefits member countries derive from the Economic Community of West African State (ECOWAS) except _______",
A: "economic cooperation",
B: "Larger market",
C: "military assistance",
D: "free ports",
answer: "D. free port",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Which of the following is not an obligation of a citizen?",
A: "payment of taxes",
B: "voting in an election",
C: "protecting public property",
D: "attending religious gathering",
answer: "D. Attending religious gathering",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. The implementation of indirect rule was supervised by the __________",
A: "Chiefs and Councils of elders",
B: "British officials",
C: "spiritual leaders of the land",
D: "educated elite",
answer: "B. British Officials",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. The electronic and print media makes their views heard on national issues through_______",
A: "public notice",
B: "adverisement",
C: "documentary",
D: "editorial commentary",
answer: "C. documentary",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Any type of restricted franchise is a violation of the principle of ________",
A: "constitutionalism",
B: "soveriegnty",
C: "political equality",
D: "editorial commentary",
answer: "C. political equality",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Public corporation can operate in a more efficient manner if they are ________",
A: "free from political interference",
B: "controlled by the judicial service commission",
C: "under the head of the civil service",
D: "controlled by the military",
answer: "A. free from political interference",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. The agency responsible for fulfilling the purpose of the state is ________",
A: "government",
B: "pressure group",
C: "public corporation",
D: "media",
answer: "A. government",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. The power of the electorate signifies _________",
A: "political sovereignty",
B: "legal sovereignty",
C: "external sovereignty",
D: "internal sovereignty",
answer: "A. political sovereignty",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. The removal of government direct control and monopoly in manufacturing and service sectors is called __________",
A: "privatization",
B: "specialization",
C: "commercialization",
D: "decentralization",
answer: "C. commercialization",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. ECOWAS monitoring group (ECOMOG)  was established to ________",
A: "recruit able-bodied men to defend West Africa",
B: "restore peace to war-torn West African countries",
C: "change bad government in West Africa",
D: "corporation of the ex-servicemen with the governor",
answer: "B. restore peace to war torn West African countries",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. The major concern of the United Nations Organization (UNO) is world ________",
A: "trade",
B: "peace",
C: "health",
D: "cooperation",
answer: "B. peace",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. Nationalist agitation in British West Africa after the World War II led to the ________",
A: "disregard for traditional rulers who supported the British",
B: "formation of political parties",
C: "killing of British administrative officials",
D: "cooperation of the ex-servicemen with the governor",
answer: "B. formation of political parties",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. An African- American who contributed greatly to the growth of nationalism  in West Africa was _______",
A: "Martin Luther King",
B: "Jesse Jackson",
C: "Nelson Mandela",
D: "William Du Bois",
answer: "C. Nelson Mandela",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. Which of the following is not a component of political culture?",
A: "Norms",
B: "Age",
C: "Beliefs",
D: "Attitudes",
answer: "B. Age",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. The following were checks on the powers of chiefs during the pre-colonial era except the __________",
A: "British Officials",
B: "Kingsmakers",
C: "Council of Elders",
D: "Age grades",
answer: "A. British Officials",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. A common feature of pre-independence constitutions of British West African colonies was the _________",
A: "existence of separation of power",
B: "governor's membership of both the legislative and executive councils",
C: "adoption of federalism",
D: "establishment of council of elders",
answer: "A. existence of separation of powers",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. Which of the following features of indirect rule contributed immensely to Nationalism in British West Africa.",
A: "Establishment of native courts",
B: "the appointment of resident district commissioners",
C: "establishment of the native courts",
D: "exclusion of the educated elites",
answer: "C. Establishment of the native courts",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. The first inter-territorial association organised by some educated African elite in the Gold Coast as the ________",
A: "Aborigine's Rights Protection Society (ARFS)",
B: "National Congress of British West Africa (NCBWA)",
C: "Movement of Educated Elites in West Africa (MEEWA)",
D: "West Africa Frontier Forces(WAFF)",
answer: "B. National Congress of British West Africa (NCBWA)",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},


]